Christopher Olcheski

linkedin.com/in/colcheski chrisolcheski.com

Full-Stack software engineer with 7+ years of experience developing and maintaining web applications. Demonstrated ability to self start and collaborate with team members while leading development on administrative and customer service tool for USPS. Continued committment to learning and growing while maintaining and developing new features for Learning A-Z products including a rewrite of their reporting modules.

Work Experience

Software Engineer II Jul 2022–Present

Learning A-Z

- Developed and maintained various parts of the application utilizing Angular, AngularJS, and PHP among other web technologies
- Headed rewrite of application reporting modules to increase value of reporting data for customers

Computer Systems Developer, Sr

Feb 2016-Jul 2022

United States Postal Service

- Led development and maintenance on administrative and customer service tool developed in Java, Oracle SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and Bootstrap while participating in an Agile development workflow
- Led development on customer service side of multiple address per personal account initiative including planning of how multiple addressing would be utilized throughout the organization and increasing the maximum addresses on an account from 1 to 5
- Developed unit testing framework for the application to comply with company standards and increased unit test coverage by 25% in the overall code base using JUnit, Mockito, PowerMock, and JaCoCo
- Automated batch jobs handling administrative tasks using IBM MQ
- Maintained fraud metrics reporting tools used for multiple government agencies

Production Coordinator Jun 2015–Feb 2016

TMG Health

- Utilized Microsoft SQL Server and Macro programs to automate report generation and claims processing
- Wrote an automated report script to generate a claims report that was being done manually saving 10 hours per week in manpower

Education

Penn State University

Bachelor of Science, Information Sciences and Technology

2013-2015

Luzerne County Community College

Associate of Science, Computer Information Systems

2011-2013

Skills

- Java EE and SE
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- HTML
- CSS

- Jenkins
- Java Persistence API (JPA)
- SQL
- WebSphere Application Server
- Apache ANT and Maven

- Sonar
- Subversion
- Git
- AngularJS and Angular
- PHP